# **Abdulraheem Quwam**

## Data Analyst

<u>quwamabdulraheem99@gmail.com</u> <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/abdulraheem-quwam</u>

## **Summary**

Accomplished Data Analyst with extensive experience in predictive modeling and data processing algorithms, as well as scripting language including python. Capable of Providing actionable business intelligence to support strategic initiatives and implement the solutions derived to improve return on investment.

## **Experience**

HAMOYE AI, Remote - Data Science Intern

JAN 2023 - PRESENT

- Identifying, analyzing, and interpreting trends or patterns in complex data using statistical techniques and providing reports on the findings of the analysis conducted on the data.
- Developed a machine learning algorithm to solve complex problems.
- Utilizing the github hosting platform for team collaboration and project management.

#### TCR Innovation, Remote - Data Science Intern

OCT 2022 - JAN 2023

- Develop machine learning algorithms for predictive maintenance.
- Performing exploration data analysis on data to drive meaningful insights.
- Develop action plans to mitigate risks in decision-making while increasing profitability by leveraging data science.

#### Neo Docto Inc, Remote - Data Analyst Intern

JUL 2022 - OCT 2022

- Utilized analytical and technical expertise to provide insights and proposals to support business improvement.
- Conducted Business analysis to understand business needs and requirements to translate into conceptual designs.

 Analyzed and produced KPI reports allowing to monitor field service and customer care center closely.

#### The Sparks Foundation, Remote - Data Science Intern

MAY 2022 - JUN 2022

- Examined Informations using the data analysis tools provided by Python to make important decisions by identifying facts and trends in data.
- Build predictive models using various machine learning tools to predict the possibility of equipment failure.

#### **EDUCATION**

University Of Ilorin, Kwara - Bsc. Economics.

Apr 2020 - Present

**Talent Model College, Lagos - SSCE. Economics.** 

MAY 2013 - JULY 2019

#### **Skills**

- Python Programming Language
- Relational Database (SQL)
- Microsoft Power BI, Microsoft Excel
- Machine Learning (Supervised, Unsupervised)
- Data Analysis, Effective Communication, Critical Thinking, Problem-Solving

## **Selected Projects**

PepsiCo Data Science Challenge
FundRaising Prediction
Employee's Churn Prediction

### **Awards**

**Top performer,** Data Science Nigeria Hackathon. Data Science Nigeria (DSN) is a frontline Artificial Intelligence (AI) non-profit committed to driving the solution-oriented application of Artificial Intelligence in Nigeria, with a focus on building world-class AI knowledge, research, and innovation ecosystem that delivers transformational research, business use applications, AI-first start-ups, employability, and good social use cases.